消灭
Exterminate!
我能看透所有时间和空间
I can see the whole of time and space,
也能看清你的每个原子
every single atom of your existence,
并将之分解
and I divide them.
博士 -别过来
Doctor! - Stay away!
告诉我你怎么了
Tell me what's going on.
我吸收了时间漩涡的全部能量
I absorbed all the energy of the time vortex,
没人承受得了这个
and no one's meant to do that.
时间领主有个小诡计
Time Lords have this little trick.
可以说是一种欺骗死神的方法吧
It's, er... sort of a way of cheating death.
只不过…
Except...
这意味着我会改变
it means I'm gonna change,
你好啊…
Hello! OK...
新牙齿 真诡异 刚说到哪了
New teeth, that's weird. So where was I?
对了 巴塞罗那
Oh, that's right! Barcelona!
神秘博士
2005 Children in Need 喜剧短片
下午6点
6 PM...
星期二
Tuesday...
十月
October...
5006年
5006...
向巴塞罗那出发
On the way to Barcelona!
现在 我看起来怎么样
Now then... what do I look like?
不 别急 别告诉我
No, no no, no...no. Don't tell me.
我看看
Let's see...
两条腿 两条胳膊 两只手
two legs, two arms, two hands...
手腕不怎么有力
Slight weakness in the dorsal tubercle.
头发 我没有秃头
Hair! I'm not bald!
喔 满头浓发啊
Oh, Oh! Big hair!
鬓角 我有鬓角了
Sideburns, I've got sideburns!
皮肤真够差的
Or really bad skin.
瘦了点 怪怪的
Little bit thinner...That's weird.
花点时间 我会习惯的
Give me time, I'll get used to it.
我…有个…胎记
I... have got... a mole.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
在肩胛骨中间 有个胎记
Between my shoulder blades, there's a mole.
没关系 我喜欢胎记
That's all right. Love the mole.
该你了 告诉我
Go on then, tell me.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是博士啊
I'm the Doctor.
不 他在哪儿
No! Where is him?
博士在哪 你把他怎么了
Where is the Doctor? What have you done to him?
你看见的 我变了啊
You saw me, I, I changed...
就在你面前变的
right in front of you.
我看到他好像…
I saw him
好像爆炸了 然后…
sort of explode, and then
你就取代了他
you replaced him,
好像是传送走了
like a... a teleport or a
或者身体置换之类的
transmat or a body swap or something.
别想骗我
You're not fooling me.
我见过这些东西
I've seen all sorts of things.
纳米基因体
Nano genes...
瓦斯族
Gelth...
斯利辛人
Slitheen...
天呐 你是斯利辛人
Oh, my God, are you a Slitheen?
我不是斯利辛人
I'm not a Slitheen.
把他还给我
Send him back.
我警告你 快把博士送回来
I'm warning you; send the Doctor back right now!
洛丝 是我
Rose, it's me.
真的是我
Honestly, it's me.
我刚刚濒临死亡
I was dying.
为了活命 我改変了身体
To save my own life I changed my body.
每一个细胞 但是…
Every single cell, but...
我还是我
it's still me.
这不是真的
You can't be.
那我怎么会记得这个
Then how could I remember this?
我对你说的第一句话
Very first word I ever said to you.
你困在地下室里
Trapped in that cellar.
被活塑料人追着跑
Surrounded by shop window dummies....
真是好久以前了
such a long time ago.
我抓住你的手
I took your hand...
我说了一个字
I said one word...
就一个字 我说…
just one word, I said...
跑
"Run".
博士
Doctor.
你好
Hello.
天呐
oh my god.
我们还没停过呢 不是吗
And we never stopped, did we?
穿梭于宇宙之间
All across the universe.
不停的跑来跑去
Running, running, running...
有一次我们必须单脚跳
One time we had to hop.
还记得吗
Do you remember?
边跳边逃命
Hopping for our lives.
对吧 跳来跳去的
Yeah? All that hopping?
记得单脚跳逃命吗
Remember hopping for your life? Yeah?!
一直跳
Hop?
就是
With the...
不记得
No?
你能变回去吗
Can you change back?
你想让我变回去
Do you want me to?
是的
Yeah.
噢
Oh.
可以吗
Can you?
不能
No.
你想离开吗
Do you want to leave?
你想要我离开吗
Do you want me to leave?
当然不是 但…
No! But...
随你选择 如果你想回家的话
your choice... if you want to go home...
取消前往巴塞罗那
Cancel Barcelona.
转向…
Change to...
伦敦 帕维尔小区
London... the Powell Estate...
就设在12月24日吧
let's say the 24th of December. .
就当是我的圣诞扎物
Consider it a Christmas present.
行了
There.
我正在回家
I'm going home?
由你决定
Up to you.
回到你妈那儿
Back to your mum...
都在等着你呢
it's all waiting.
炸鱼薯条 土豆泥 豆酱面包
Fish and chips, sausage and mash, beans on toast...
不对 圣诞节 火鸡
no, Christmas! Turkey!
然而
Although...
以我对你妈的了解
having met your mother...
能有坚果面包就不错了
nut loaf would be more appropriate.
你笑了
Was that a smile?
没有
No.
绝对笑了
That was a smile...
我没有
No it wasn't.
你确实笑了
You smiled...
才没有
No, I didn't.
拜托 我只不过是变了个样子嘛
Oh, come on. All I did was change.
我又不是…
I didn't...Uh oh.
什么
What?
我说…
I said I...
你还好吗
Are you alright?
那是什么
What's that?
这次重生的确有点不对劲
the change is going a bit wrong and all.
我觉得 我们应该回去
Look... maybe we should go back.
去找杰克上校 他知道怎么办
Let's go and find Captain Jack, he'd know what to do.
啊…他没空
Gah, he's busy!
他有很多事要做 忙着重建地球
He's got plenty to do rebuilding the Earth!
哦 我好久没用过这个了
I haven't used this one in years.
你在干什么
What're you doing?!
加速再加速 这就对了
Putting on a bit of speed! That's it!
我的好飞船啊
My beautiful ship!
再快点 好丫头
Come on, faster! That's a girl!
继续加速 想不想打破时间极限
Faster! Wanna to break the time limit?!
停下
Stop it!
别这么死板嘛 找点乐子吧
Ah, don't be so dull... let's have a bit of fun!
把时间漩涡撕成两半
Let's rip through that vortex!
这次重生出问题了
The regeneration's going wrong.
我控制不住自己
I can't stop myself. .
啊 我的头
Ah, my head...
再快点 发动所有引擎
Faster! Let's open those engines!
那是什么声音
What's that?
要坠毁了 哈哈哈
We're gonna crash land!
那你想想办法呀
Well then, do something!
太晚了 已经失控了
Too late! Out of control.
爱死你了
Oh, I love it! Hot dawg!
你会害死我们俩的
You're gonna kill us!
抓紧了 我们来了
Hold on tight, here we go!
平安夜
Christmas Eve...!